IAN HORN

 $horn.imh@gmail.com \diamond linkedin:ianhorn \diamond (650) \cdot 544 \cdot 4676 \diamond imh.github.io$

Experienced ML generalist with a strong track record of leading projects through their lifecycle as engineer, data scientist, and occasionally PM. I've had a lot of impact by taking initiative on problems that are falling through the cracks.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Stitch Fix 2015 - Present

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

San Francisco, CA

Seven years of personalized fashion spanning NLP, causal inference, CV, and recsys. Selected Highlights:

- · Built long-missing infrastructure for image data. It was immediately adopted by several teams and now powers the org's CV work.
- · Enabled new kinds of recommendations on our home page by collecting new datasets and building novel CV models on them. I also built the recommender for this.
- · Combined causal inference and supervised learning to automatically intervene before bad shipments reached clients.

Swift Navigation

2013 - 2015

Lead R&D Engineer (First employee)

San Francisco, CA

Embedded estimation algorithms for high precision GPS systems

- · Developed algorithms for real-time localization with 1 cm precision.
- · Implemented estimation algorithms on resource-constrained embedded platforms.
- \cdot Developed software-in-the-loop back testing framework for model validation.

Remilon, LLC (now Study.com)

2012 - 2013

Technical Data Analyst

Mountain View, CA

Constrained optimization for ad ranking

- · Built a contextual bandit that formed the backbone of our company's ad ranking system for years.
- · Wrote numerical optimization code for fast large scale model fitting.
- · ETL, dashboarding, and experimental analysis.

Joby Energy (now Joby Aviation) Systems Engineer

2009 - 2011

Santa Cruz, CA

Statistics and optimization for eVTOL (flying cars)

- · Designed aircraft propellers using numerical optimization methods.
- · Developed physical simulation of aircraft.
- · Performed experimental statistical validation of aircraft wings and propellers.

UC Santa Cruz (Santa Cruz Institute for Particle Physics) 2006 - 2008 Research Assistant Santa Cruz, CA

Electrical engineering support for a particle detector at CERN/LHC

· Didn't create any planet-destroying black-holes.

SELECTED SIDE PROJECTS

- · Diffusion-based LLMs for writing sci-fi novels, focused on efficiently expanding context length.
- · Probabilistic programming DSL, analogous to autograd for PGMs.
- · Program induction. A small lambda calculus + deep RL = learning programs from data.
- · Hipsterplot: A ridiculous ASCII plotter that is somehow my most popular project on github.

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Cruz

B.S. Applied Physics

Thesis: Inferring rates of unobserved transitions in a 1D continuous Markov process